# Michael Poli

poli@stanford.edu  $\cdot$  +10 9975 2378 GitHub  $\cdot$  Google Scholar  $\cdot$  Website  $\cdot$  Twitter

# deep learning | generative models | numerical optimization | optimal control

#### **OVERVIEW**

I am a CS Ph.D. student at Stanford University. My research interests lie at the intersection of deep learning, generative modeling, numerical optimization, dynamical systems and optimal control. Through a dynamical system perspective of learning, my goal is to develop novel neural network architectures, improve training efficiency and constrain the model to a set of desiderata. I have recently focused on wrapping numerical methods in neural architectures: neural differential equations and implicit models.

#### **EDUCATION**

PhD, Computer Science, Stanford University (2021 – TBD)

M.S, Industrial and Systems Engineering, KAIST (2018 – 2020)

**B.Eng.**, Control Theory, Tongji University (2015 – 2017)

B.Eng., Automation Engineering, University of Bologna (2014–2017)

Palo Alto, USA Daejeon, South Korea Shanghai, China Bologna, Italy

#### Industry Experience

#### NAVER AI, Research Scientist Intern (Feb 2021 – Sep 2021)

Seoul, South Korea

- Developed a new method for system identification of multi-mode stochastic hybrid systems (NeurIPS 2021)
- Worked on analyses of biases towards shortcut learning cues in computer vision models.

KAIST, Research Fellow (Sep 2020 – Sep 2021)

Daejeon, South Korea

- Development on the core simulation architecture for greenhouse dynamics.
- Mentoring research engineers and software developers.

Koidra.ai, Research Scientist, Part-Time (Sep 2020 - Feb 2021)

Seattle, USA (remote)

- Development on the core simulation architecture for greenhouse dynamics.
- Mentoring research engineers and software developers.

Neuri.ai, Research Engineer Intern, (Jun 2019 – Oct 2019)

Singapore

• Developed deep learning and reinforcement learning models for end-to-end FX trading systems.

## Conference and Journal Publications

[1] Michael Poli\*, Stefano Massaroli\*, Luca Scimeca, Seong Joon Oh, Sanghyuk Chun, Atsushi Yamashita, Hajime Asama, Jinkyoo Park, Animesh Garg

Neural Hybrid Automata: Learning Dynamics with Multiple Modes and Stochastic Transitions Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 34 (NeurIPS 2021)

[2] Stefano Massaroli\*, Michael Poli\*, Sho Sonoda, Taiji Suzuki, Jinkyoo Park, Atsushi Yamashita, Hajime Asama Differentiable Multiple Shooting Layers Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 34 (NeurIPS 2021)

[3] Stefano Massaroli\*, Michael Poli\*, Stefano Peluchetti\*, Jinkyoo Park, Atsushi Yamashita, Hajime Asama Learning Stochastic Optimal Policies via Gradient Descent 59th IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (CDC 2020) IEEE Control Systems Letters (L-CSS)

[4] Stefano Massaroli\*, **Michael Poli**\*, Jinkyoo Park, Atsushi Yamashita, Hajime Asama Dissecting Neural ODEs

Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 33 (NeurIPS 2020) - Oral (1% of submissions)

[5] Michael Poli\*, Stefano Massaroli\*, Atsushi Yamashita, Hajime Asama, Jinkyoo Park Hypersolvers: Towards Fast Continuous—Depth Models Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 33 (NeurIPS 2020)

[6] Michael Poli, Jinkyoo Park, Ilija Ilievski

WATTNet: Learning to Trade FX via Hierarchical Spatio-Temporal Representation of Highly Multivariate Time Series International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI 2020)

[7] Stefano Massaroli\*, **Michael Poli**\*, Federico Califano, Angela Faragasso, Jinkyoo Park, Atsushi Yamashita, Hajime Asama

Port-Hamiltonian Approach to Neural Network Training 58th IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (CDC 2019)

- [1] Federico Berto, Stefano Massaroli, **Michael Poli**, Jinkyoo Park Port-Hamiltonian Approach to Neural Network Training NeurIPS Workshop on The Symbiosis of Deep Learning and Differential Equations (2021) – Spotlight (21%)
- [2] Michael Poli\*, Stefano Massaroli\*, Atsushi Yamashita, Hajime Asama, Jinkyoo Park, Stefano Ermon TorchDyn: Implicit Models and Neural Numerical Methods in PyTorch Preprint (2021)
- [3] Stefano Massaroli\*, Michael Poli\*, Michelangelo Bin, Jinkyoo Park, Atsushi Yamashita, Hajime Asama Optimal Energy Shaping via Neural Approximators Preprint (2021)
- [4] Daehoon Gwak, Gyuhyeon Sim, Michael Poli, Stefano Massaroli, Jaegul Choo, Edward Choi Neural Ordinary Differential Equations for Intervention Modeling Preprint (2021)
- [5] Michael Poli\*, Stefano Massaroli\*, Atsushi Yamashita, Hajime Asama, Jinkyoo Park Port-Hamiltonian Gradient Flows ICLR Workshop on the Integration of Deep Neural Models and Differential Equations (2020)
- [6] Stefano Massaroli\*, Michael Poli\*, Jinkyoo Park, Atsushi Yamashita, Hajime Asama Neural Ordinary Differential Equation Value Networks for Parametrized Action Spaces ICLR Workshop on the Integration of Deep Neural Models and Differential Equations (2020)
- [7] Michael Poli\*, Stefano Massaroli\*, Atsushi Yamashita, Hajime Asama, Jinkyoo Park Graph Neural Ordinary Differential Equations AAAI International Workshop on Deep Learning on Graphs, DLGMA (2020) – Contributed Talk (10%)
- [8] Michael Poli, Jinkyoo Park, Ilija Ilievski WATTNet: Learning to Trade FX via Hierarchical Spatio-Temporal Representation of Highly Multivariate Time Series AAAI Workshop on Knowledge Discovery from Unstructured Data in Finance (2020)
- [9] Stefano Massaroli\*, Michael Poli\*, Michelangelo Bin, Jinkyoo Park, Atsushi Yamashita, Hajime Asama Stable Neural Flows Preprint (2020)

## PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES:

Reviewer: NeurIPS (2021), ICLR (2022), AISTATS (2022), ICML (2021)

Mentoring: Federico Berto (KAIST IE, 2020-22)

Jiyoung Lee (KAIST AL 2020-22)

Jiyoung Lee (KAIST AI, 2020-22) Chuanbo Hua (KAIST IE, 2020-22)

Invited Speaker: Continuous-Depth Learning: A System-Theoretic Perspective (2020, HKML S3E4)

Learning with Differential Equations (2021, Harvard Computational Science)

#### References:

prof. Edward Choi: mp2893 at gmail.com

prof. Jinkyoo Park: jinkyoo.park at kaist.ac.kr

prof. Claudio Melchiorri: claudio.melchiorri at unibo.it

KAIST, Google KAIST, Stanford University of Bologna